Jonathan Navarrete

7604020876 | navar045@cougars.csusm.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-navarrete-427a35b3

Summary

Data scientist with experience spearheading statistical modeling methodologies for consulting projects. Projects range from fraud detection to biotech R&D. Many of the projects I work on require working with large complex data sets, conducting longitudinal data analysis and data mining.

Education

M.S. STATISTICS | 2016 | SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY

B.A. ECONOMICS | 2013 | CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, SAN MARCOS

A. A. MATH/SCIENCE | 2010 | PALOMAR COLLEGE

CERTIFIED APACHE SPARK DEVELOPER | 2016 | DATABRICKS & O'REILLY MEDIA, LICENSE 1.X-0645

Technical Skills

- · Advanced statistical and predictive analytics experience
- · Scripting/Programming languages: R, Python, Scala, SQL, C++, JavaScript
- · Databases: SQL Server, MySQL, Redshift
- · Apache Spark Developer certified
- · Linux/Unix shell scripting
- · Amazon Web Services (Security & Architecture, EMR, EC2, S3, Redshift)

Relevant Experience

ANALYTICAL SCIENTIST | FICO | NOVEMBER 2016 - PRESENT (4 MONTHS)

Analytical scientist working in the Analytics Engineering Group and Modeling Services as part of the Falcon Fraud services.

- Assist modeling team with data prep before modeling, and post-production troubleshooting and investigation on live models. This includes the analysis of large amounts of historical data.
- · Assist with model live models by performing production data validations and score distribution analysis of models in production.
- Assist with client meetings to investigate and resolve production data problems.

DATA SCIENCE ANALYST | ALGEBRAIX DATA CORPORATION | JANUARY 2016 - NOVEMBER 2016 (11 MONTHS)

As data science analyst, I assisted consultant clients identify solutions to business research questions. I worked closely with clients to develop statistically sound data analysis methodologies, and provide timely results to drive future business strategies. In collaboration with statistical analyses, In-house Statistician and lead statistical modeler

RESEARCH ANALYST | PALOMAR COLLEGE | JULY 2013 - FEBRUARY 2016 (2 YEARS 8 MONTHS)

As research analyst for a grant funded program at Palomar College, I took charge in leading the way to a more data driven approach in evaluating outreach and interventions programs, and suggesting programs that positive databacked results. In addition, I lead the training sessions for technical training for new staff.

RESEARCH FELLOW | LOS ANGELES URBAN NATURAL RESOURCES SUSTAINABILITY CENTER | JANUARY 2015 - DECEMBER 2015 (1 YEAR)

As first recipient of the LA Center Fellowship, I lead a geospatial analytics project to analyze natural resource demand for the highest urbanized national forest. Utilized R and ArcGIS to measure and display demand.

- · Survey methodology and statistical analysis
- $\cdot\,$ GIS and Spatial Analysis of the S. California Agency of Governments region
- · Conduct literature and background research for qualitative and quantitative projects

ANALYTICS INTERN | BUSINESSONLINE | JUNE 2015 - AUGUST 2015 (3 MONTHS)

As intern, I lead data-mining and geospatial analytics using R and GIS software to identify new target locations for future marketing strategies. At the end of internship, I presented findings to

- · Leverage large data sets from internal and external databases to mine for key insights
- · Defining business cases and solutions to business problems
- · Improved overall business analytics methodology

RESEARCH ASSISTANT | CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, SAN MARCOS | JULY 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2016

References

Available Upon Request.